<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
    <title>fragiledata.co.uk</title>
    <link href="https://fragiledata.github.io/StaticHost/feed.xml" rel="self" />
    <link href="https://fragiledata.github.io/StaticHost" />
    <updated>2022-05-25T19:54:03+01:00</updated>
    <author>
        <name>fragiledata</name>
    </author>
    <id>https://fragiledata.github.io/StaticHost</id>

    <entry>
        <title>Outputting Data to Snowflake; Comparative Methods with Alteryx</title>
        <author>
            <name>fragiledata</name>
        </author>
        <link href="https://fragiledata.github.io/StaticHost/outputting-data-to-snowflake-comparative-methods-with-alteryx/"/>
        <id>https://fragiledata.github.io/StaticHost/outputting-data-to-snowflake-comparative-methods-with-alteryx/</id>
            <category term="Tools and Tech"/>
            <category term="Data Engineering"/>

        <updated>2022-05-25T19:42:59+01:00</updated>
            <summary>
                <![CDATA[
                        <img src="https://fragiledata.github.io/StaticHost/media/posts/40/image-6.png" alt="A simple Alteryx workflow showing four different connections to SnowFlake databases." />
                    My firm have recently signed up with Snowflake, so on a spare&hellip;
                ]]>
            </summary>
        <content type="html">
            <![CDATA[
                    <img src="https://fragiledata.github.io/StaticHost/media/posts/40/image-6.png" alt="A simple Alteryx workflow showing four different connections to SnowFlake databases." />
                <p><!-- wp:paragraph --></p>
<p>My firm have recently signed up with Snowflake, so on a spare afternoon I decided to compare the different ways you can connect data to Snowflake from Alteryx. I'm doing this with some Kickstarter data I found on <a href="https://data.world/rdowns26/kickstarter-campaigns">data.world</a>; I'm breaking the data down into four tables, and writing each table with a different method.</p>
<p><!-- /wp:paragraph --></p>
<p><!-- wp:image {"id":621,"sizeSlug":"large","linkDestination":"none"} --></p>
<figure class="wp-block-image size-large"><figure class="wp-image-621"><img loading="lazy"  src="https://fragiledata.github.io/StaticHost/media/posts/40/image-6.png" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" srcset="https://fragiledata.github.io/StaticHost/media/posts/40/responsive/image-6-xs.png 300w ,https://fragiledata.github.io/StaticHost/media/posts/40/responsive/image-6-sm.png 480w ,https://fragiledata.github.io/StaticHost/media/posts/40/responsive/image-6-md.png 768w ,https://fragiledata.github.io/StaticHost/media/posts/40/responsive/image-6-lg.png 1024w"  alt="An Alteryx workflow showing four different methods of Snowflake output."></figure>
<figcaption>An Alteryx workflow showing four different methods of Snowflake output.</figcaption>
</figure>
<p><!-- /wp:image --></p>
<p><!-- wp:heading {"level":3} --></p>
<h3>The ODBC connector using a regular output tool</h3>
<p><!-- /wp:heading --></p>
<p><!-- wp:paragraph --></p>
<p><em>(note: both Snowflake and Alteryx do not recommend this for large data operations)</em></p>
<p><!-- /wp:paragraph --></p>
<p><!-- wp:paragraph --></p>
<p>Using Alteryx's regular output tool, I've connected with a standard ODBC connection for Snowflake to ingest my "summary information" table, which is a load of rows with summary Kickstarter project information on. I had set up the connection as a DSN on my computer during the internal training we had, so I just reused that.</p>
<p><!-- /wp:paragraph --></p>
<p><!-- wp:paragraph --></p>
<p>Pro: didn't really have to think much about setting it up after the first time.</p>
<p><!-- /wp:paragraph --></p>
<p><!-- wp:paragraph --></p>
<p>Con: the ODBC driver writes one record at a time, so twenty thousand records and 11 fields took twenty minutes. It is not a fast way of doing things; I'm uploading a lot of rows from a flat file perspective, but dust from a Big Data perspective, and this took a while. There must be a better way....</p>
<p><!-- /wp:paragraph --></p>
<p><!-- wp:heading {"level":3} --></p>
<h3>The ODBC Bulk Loader, using a regular output tool</h3>
<p><!-- /wp:heading --></p>
<p><!-- wp:paragraph --></p>
<p>Other members of my firm encountered this problem early on and shortly discovered the bulk loader connection. As the name suggests, this is meant to be faster than the regular ODBC connection and is designed for bulk inputs, like I'm doing here. The original ODBC input works one line at a time, but the bulk loader stages it before contacting the database.</p>
<p><!-- /wp:paragraph --></p>
<p><!-- wp:paragraph --></p>
<p>When I selected the bulk loader and brought up the below interface, I thought it was important to remember two things - you can select "local" for staging if you don't have an AWS bucket lying about, and you can still use Pre and Post SQL statements in the output tool.</p>
<p><!-- /wp:paragraph --></p>
<p><!-- wp:image {"align":"center","id":607,"sizeSlug":"large","linkDestination":"none"} --></p>
<div class="wp-block-image">
<figure class="aligncenter size-large"><figure class="wp-image-607"><img loading="lazy"  src="https://fragiledata.github.io/StaticHost/media/posts/40/image-2.png" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" srcset="https://fragiledata.github.io/StaticHost/media/posts/40/responsive/image-2-xs.png 300w ,https://fragiledata.github.io/StaticHost/media/posts/40/responsive/image-2-sm.png 480w ,https://fragiledata.github.io/StaticHost/media/posts/40/responsive/image-2-md.png 768w ,https://fragiledata.github.io/StaticHost/media/posts/40/responsive/image-2-lg.png 1024w"  alt="An image showing the Snowflake Bulk Loader interface, asking the user to select a way of staging the data."></figure>
<figcaption>An image showing the Snowflake Bulk Loader interface, asking the user to select a way of staging the data.</figcaption>
</figure>
</div>
<p><!-- /wp:image --></p>
<p><!-- wp:paragraph --></p>
<p>Pro: Yes, definitely faster. This was the same number of rows (but only 5 columns) and took 5.1 seconds.</p>
<p><!-- /wp:paragraph --></p>
<p><!-- wp:paragraph --></p>
<p>Con: remembering that it is there in the first place.</p>
<p><!-- /wp:paragraph --></p>
<p><!-- wp:paragraph --></p>
<p>This is actually the second resort of Snowflake and Alteryx's recommendations. The first is our quiet and weird cousin, the In-DB tools.</p>
<p><!-- /wp:paragraph --></p>
<p><!-- wp:heading {"level":3} --></p>
<h3>Stream and Write with the In-DB tools</h3>
<p><!-- /wp:heading --></p>
<p><!-- wp:paragraph --></p>
<p>Alteryx + Snowflake's <a href="https://www.alteryx.com/whitepaper/best-practices-for-using-alteryx-with-snowflake">documentation for working together</a> recommends getting to the InDB tools as fast/as much as possible. This effectively shifts the "thought" of the process onto the DB and therefore onto Snowflake's warehouse, which makes sense in an enterprise environment. But I'm just loading in data? How does it help me?</p>
<p><!-- /wp:paragraph --></p>
<p><!-- wp:paragraph --></p>
<p>When configuring the InDB tools to stream the data out and write it to the database, the first thing I have to configure relates to the right InDB connections - and the write string defaults to the bulk loader, so you don't have to think about picking the right one. It also makes the option to change the data chunk size much clearer as well.</p>
<p><!-- /wp:paragraph --></p>
<p><!-- wp:image {"align":"center","id":610,"sizeSlug":"large","linkDestination":"none"} --></p>
<div class="wp-block-image">
<figure class="aligncenter size-large"><figure class="wp-image-610"><img loading="lazy"  src="https://fragiledata.github.io/StaticHost/media/posts/40/image-3.png" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" srcset="https://fragiledata.github.io/StaticHost/media/posts/40/responsive/image-3-xs.png 300w ,https://fragiledata.github.io/StaticHost/media/posts/40/responsive/image-3-sm.png 480w ,https://fragiledata.github.io/StaticHost/media/posts/40/responsive/image-3-md.png 768w ,https://fragiledata.github.io/StaticHost/media/posts/40/responsive/image-3-lg.png 1024w"  alt="A screenshot of an Alteryx configuration window, showing the bulk load chunk size is at 128mb."></figure>
<figcaption>A screenshot of an Alteryx configuration window, showing the bulk load chunk size is at 128mb.</figcaption>
</figure>
</div>
<p><!-- /wp:image --></p>
<p><!-- wp:paragraph --></p>
<p>Pro: Super speedy to write - this took about 6 seconds, which was creating a temp table and then creating the real table.</p>
<p><!-- /wp:paragraph --></p>
<p><!-- wp:paragraph --></p>
<p>Con: I tend to configure my computer DSNs with only the mandatory parameters (e.g. no database or schema) and then configure them in the tools I use at the time. The InDB tools were not a massive fan of this method and means I changed the configuration of my DSNs a few times to ensure it wrote the table to the right place.</p>
<p><!-- /wp:paragraph --></p>
<p><!-- wp:heading {"level":3} --></p>
<h3>Output with excel, and then upload</h3>
<p><!-- /wp:heading --></p>
<p><!-- wp:paragraph --></p>
<p>Of course, the last of all last resorts. Sometimes you have to do things the manual way, so let's see how it goes. I have a table of web assets for the Kickstarter projects which also need to be uploaded to Snowflake. Snowflakes manual file upload service can take standard flat files (csv, json and the like), but nothing as jazzy as an excel file.</p>
<p><!-- /wp:paragraph --></p>
<p><!-- wp:image {"align":"center","id":613,"sizeSlug":"large","linkDestination":"none"} --></p>
<div class="wp-block-image">
<figure class="aligncenter size-large"><figure class="wp-image-613"><img loading="lazy"  src="https://fragiledata.github.io/StaticHost/media/posts/40/image-4.png" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" srcset="https://fragiledata.github.io/StaticHost/media/posts/40/responsive/image-4-xs.png 300w ,https://fragiledata.github.io/StaticHost/media/posts/40/responsive/image-4-sm.png 480w ,https://fragiledata.github.io/StaticHost/media/posts/40/responsive/image-4-md.png 768w ,https://fragiledata.github.io/StaticHost/media/posts/40/responsive/image-4-lg.png 1024w"  alt="An image of Snowflake's manual data loading pane, where the load options give the user a choice as to what to do if there is an error parsing the file."></figure>
<figcaption>Aha, this is interesting.</figcaption>
</figure>
</div>
<p><!-- /wp:image --></p>
<p><!-- wp:paragraph --></p>
<p>My last component of the data is some supplementary information which was encoded in a JSON format in the data. Unaltered, this comes to about 174mb as a csv file (which is too large for Snowflake), so reformatted the data into a simple structure (loading JSONs will be for another time!). To load the data, you must create the table first, and then the "load data" option will become available on the Tables tool bar. Specify a schema and what it should do in the face of errors, and that's it.</p>
<p><!-- /wp:paragraph --></p>
<p><!-- wp:paragraph --></p>
<p>Only in my case, that wasn't it. There was a lot of trial and error going on on my part to understand the limitations of flat file upload, such that I've concluded the best configurations for me were a pipe delimited file with UTF-8 encoding. I also couldn't find the file size limits within Snowflake's documentation very easily, such that my knowledge on this is "more than 5mb but less than 174mb", which isn't particularly fine tuned. In a way though, I think it's good that uploading data as a flat file isn't <em>too </em>easy, because ideally we shouldn't just be throwing tables at the database and seeing what sticks.</p>
<p><!-- /wp:paragraph --></p>
<p><!-- wp:paragraph --></p>
<p>Pros: straight forward process</p>
<p><!-- /wp:paragraph --></p>
<p><!-- wp:paragraph --></p>
<p>Cons: actually quite fiddly in some of the parameters.</p>
<p><!-- /wp:paragraph --></p>
<p><!-- wp:paragraph --></p>
<p>To conclude, the best method for posting data to Snowflake is the bulk loader, whether using InDB or regular output tools. Use other methods at your peril!</p>
<p><!-- /wp:paragraph --></p>
            ]]>
        </content>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title>The Manners of Webscraping - The Short Version for Busy Analysts</title>
        <author>
            <name>fragiledata</name>
        </author>
        <link href="https://fragiledata.github.io/StaticHost/the-manners-of-webscraping-the-short-version-for-busy-analysts/"/>
        <id>https://fragiledata.github.io/StaticHost/the-manners-of-webscraping-the-short-version-for-busy-analysts/</id>
            <category term="Tools and Tech"/>
            <category term="Data Analysis"/>

        <updated>2022-05-25T19:45:52+01:00</updated>
            <summary>
                <![CDATA[
                        <img src="https://fragiledata.github.io/StaticHost/media/posts/39/image.png" alt="EDI, a robot character from Mass Effect, explains she cannot turn to crime for money, because that would look bad on a resume." />
                    The ethics of web scraping is not an unknown topic in the&hellip;
                ]]>
            </summary>
        <content type="html">
            <![CDATA[
                    <img src="https://fragiledata.github.io/StaticHost/media/posts/39/image.png" alt="EDI, a robot character from Mass Effect, explains she cannot turn to crime for money, because that would look bad on a resume." />
                <p><!-- wp:paragraph --></p>
<p>The ethics of web scraping is not an unknown topic in the discourse of development and coding (<a href="https://fragiledata.co.uk/2020/02/22/should-i-scrape-this-planning-notes-on-inspecting-websites/">even I've mentioned this before</a>), with a lot of material out there explaining the different moral positions of scraping. At work, our short hand to new analysts is often to be polite - fucking up someone else's server is rude. But when you're new to something, how do you know what's going to fuck it up? You're learning about APIs while you're learning about a thousand other things and those 70 pages of documentation for an end point you just want to look into seems like a lot, because right now even the best written API material is 90% completely meaningless to you. A subsequent refrain after that is to check terms and conditions or robots.txt, but they too, whether by legalese or googlese, are also 90% meaningless to a new analyst.</p>
<p><!-- /wp:paragraph --></p>
<p><!-- wp:paragraph --></p>
<p>I was on Github looking at something else (as always) when I saw someone I follow forking an R repository called <a href="https://github.com/dmi3kno/polite">Polite</a>. It was written by Dmytry Perepolkin and is a small package to enable R users to web scrape pages politely. Dmytry's markdown to explain the pillars of politeness are well written and absolutely applicable to the wider corners of scraping that a lot of analysts do using tools like Alteryx.</p>
<p><!-- /wp:paragraph --></p>
<p><!-- wp:list {"ordered":true,"start":0} --></p>
<ol start="0">
<li>Introduce Yourself (if required)</li>
<li>Seeking Permission</li>
<li>Taking Slowly</li>
<li>Never Ask Twice</li>
</ol>
<p><!-- /wp:list --></p>
<p><!-- wp:paragraph --></p>
<p>Within Alteryx and other "no code" type data handling tools, API query workflows can become quite complex very quickly, particularly if the workflow is having to handle a particular authentication method (such as session tokens) or forms of pagination, which generally entail writing iterative calls. I have been in discussions with colleagues and clients on occasion where someone will say "why don't we just...." in a certain way, which will usually involve violating one of the above rules - seeking permission is the most common one, because people often feel that since they can look at the website as a user, what's the difference between looking at it as a user and as a machine?</p>
<p><!-- /wp:paragraph --></p>
<p><!-- wp:image {"id":583,"sizeSlug":"large","linkDestination":"none","ampLightbox":false} --></p>
<figure class="wp-block-image size-large"><figure class="wp-image-583"><img loading="lazy"  src="https://fragiledata.github.io/StaticHost/media/posts/39/image.png" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" srcset="https://fragiledata.github.io/StaticHost/media/posts/39/responsive/image-xs.png 300w ,https://fragiledata.github.io/StaticHost/media/posts/39/responsive/image-sm.png 480w ,https://fragiledata.github.io/StaticHost/media/posts/39/responsive/image-md.png 768w ,https://fragiledata.github.io/StaticHost/media/posts/39/responsive/image-lg.png 1024w"  alt="EDI, a robotic character from Mass Effect 3, says &quot;I am not formally employed. I have no legal standing in Citadel space.&quot; to explain the difference between humans and robots using an electronic service."></figure>
<figcaption>You can sell advertising to keep the site running to a user, but machines (at the moment) cannot participate in our ad marketing system. Picture from Mass Effect 3, copyright EA.</figcaption>
</figure>
<p><!-- /wp:image --></p>
<p><!-- wp:paragraph --></p>
<p>Although in that previous blog post I pointed at another article on Medium where James Densmore writes a <a href="https://towardsdatascience.com/ethics-in-web-scraping-b96b18136f01">set of guidelines</a> for scrapers and scrapees, I like this four item format for its brevity, and plain rules which make sense to any analyst (though please read those guidelines!).</p>
<p><!-- /wp:paragraph --></p>
<p><!-- wp:paragraph --></p>
<p>The idea of introducing yourself is one that is is the hardest to teach a new analyst. Partly because, as above, I don't necessarily need an account to browse Booking.com or AirBnB, but also because the idea of sessions, handshakes, "users" and the like are the concealed cookie crumbs we drop across the internet, disguised by our browsers - AirBnB might not know exactly who you are, but they do know if you've been there before. This isn't something we particularly notice until our AirBnB searches start following us around the web.</p>
<p><!-- /wp:paragraph --></p>
<p><!-- wp:paragraph --></p>
<p>"Ask Permission" is a bit easier to understand because permission generally isn't concealed to users when interacting with software. Working out which permissions you need can be a different story depending on the complexity of the API (e.g. if permissions are tied to specific user profiles), but most analysts can start working through this quickly.</p>
<p><!-- /wp:paragraph --></p>
<p><!-- wp:paragraph --></p>
<p>"Taking slowly" is one of my favourites because this is so many analysts practical introduction to the requirement of iterative or paced functions, and therefore their first real use case of how to build these in something like Alteryx. It's also a very useful way to establish the idea of data as a commodity which takes time and space to be transmitted, which can be very hard to explain when, for obvious reasons, very few people have actually seen server infrastructure in real life.</p>
<p><!-- /wp:paragraph --></p>
<p><!-- wp:paragraph --></p>
<p>Lastly, "Never Ask Twice". The joy that went up in our office when Alteryx unveiled their cache in workflow feature in 2018.3 was genuine excitement, because when you're mindful of taking slowly, you know that every time you run that workflow you are eating into precious politeness points just because of something downstream not quite looking right. As practice, it is also an invaluable way of teaching our consultants to consider the longevity of their data pipeline by ensuring that the pipeline has exception handling or accommodations for requirements which might result in "asking twice" situations occurring - such as diverting a copy of the raw data to a lake before transformation.</p>
<p><!-- /wp:paragraph --></p>
            ]]>
        </content>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title>The Ethics of Overtime in Technology</title>
        <author>
            <name>fragiledata</name>
        </author>
        <link href="https://fragiledata.github.io/StaticHost/the-ethics-of-overtime-in-technology/"/>
        <id>https://fragiledata.github.io/StaticHost/the-ethics-of-overtime-in-technology/</id>
            <category term="Behavioural Economics"/>

        <updated>2022-05-25T19:49:59+01:00</updated>
            <summary>
                <![CDATA[
                        <img src="https://fragiledata.github.io/StaticHost/media/posts/38/crunchie_bar.jpg" alt="A crunchie bar with the centre exposed." />
                    Recently, I took on the mantle of teaching data ethics and security&hellip;
                ]]>
            </summary>
        <content type="html">
            <![CDATA[
                    <img src="https://fragiledata.github.io/StaticHost/media/posts/38/crunchie_bar.jpg" alt="A crunchie bar with the centre exposed." />
                <p><!-- wp:paragraph --></p>
<p>Recently, I took on the mantle of teaching data ethics and security to colleagues who join my company. Some people study this for their entire lifetime, so what we cover in a day isn't meant to be an entire ethical guideline of how to work, but a jump start into taking responsibility for their own decisions about how to work securely and ethically. Amongst other things, we cover;</p>
<p><!-- /wp:paragraph --></p>
<p><!-- wp:list --></p>
<ul>
<li>The basics and principles of (UK) GDPR.</li>
<li>What does it mean to work securely?</li>
<li>The difference between working ethically in one's own work, the work the company does as a whole, and the contextual situation that those occur in.</li>
<li>What techniques can we explicitly use in pipelines, visualisations and copy to work in an ethical way.</li>
</ul>
<p><!-- /wp:list --></p>
<p><!-- wp:paragraph --></p>
<p>The training runs over a whole day, but I still feel there's so much I can't cover. Making some tea this morning, I realised one of the really important ones was an item that comes up at work under the radar a lot, which is the ethics of overtime.</p>
<p><!-- /wp:paragraph --></p>
<p><!-- wp:heading {"level":3} --></p>
<h3>What do you mean this comes up a lot?</h3>
<p><!-- /wp:heading --></p>
<p><!-- wp:paragraph --></p>
<p>Mostly, when it comes up under the radar. Searching for "Ethics of overtime" tends to focus on sociological and management studies looking at whether or not overtime should be paid, and whether or not it diminishes the productivity of staff doing it a lot, and some legal items examining how overtime can "fit" with labour legislation. However, labour legislation is not a common chat topic in our office - indeed, we don't often discuss whether or not overtime is the <em>right</em> thing to do. Instead, I'd like to take you to a different district of technology land, where this has a name, and a lot more scrutiny.</p>
<p><!-- /wp:paragraph --></p>
<p><!-- wp:image {"id":567,"sizeSlug":"large","linkDestination":"none"} --></p>
<figure class="wp-block-image size-large"><figure class="wp-image-567"><img loading="lazy"  src="https://fragiledata.github.io/StaticHost/media/posts/38/crunchie_bar.jpg" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" srcset="https://fragiledata.github.io/StaticHost/media/posts/38/responsive/crunchie_bar-xs.jpg 300w ,https://fragiledata.github.io/StaticHost/media/posts/38/responsive/crunchie_bar-sm.jpg 480w ,https://fragiledata.github.io/StaticHost/media/posts/38/responsive/crunchie_bar-md.jpg 768w ,https://fragiledata.github.io/StaticHost/media/posts/38/responsive/crunchie_bar-lg.jpg 1024w"  alt="Picture of a chocolate bar from the UK, which is called &quot;Crunchie&quot;."></figure>
<figcaption>By Adambro - Own work, CC BY 3.0</figcaption>
</figure>
<p><!-- /wp:image --></p>
<p><!-- wp:paragraph --></p>
<p>Crunch, in game development, is the unfortunate practice of huge amounts of overtime done in the closing stages of development in order to get the product ready to meet a deadline (usually a shipping date). Crunch entered popular internet discourse with an <a href="https://ea-spouse.livejournal.com/274.html">online journal</a> started by "EA Spouse" Erin Hoffman in 2004, which detailed her partner's unreasonable working situation at Electronic Arts, a large game publisher. Ten years later in 2015, Ian Williams in The Guardian <a href="https://www.theguardian.com/technology/2015/feb/18/crunched-games-industry-exploiting-workforce-ea-spouse-software">revisited the subject</a> and found that crunching had most definitely not gone away, and very recently famed "no-crunch" developer CD Projekt Red <a href="https://www.polygon.com/2020/10/7/21505804/cyberpunk-2077-cd-projekt-red-crunch-youtube-jason-schreier-labor-the-witcher-3">broke this internal rule</a> when trying to rustle up Cyberpunk 2077 in time for Christmas 2020, resulting in one of the most spectacular blow-outs of expectations in video game history. It's not rocket science to say that crunching is unethical - it symbolic of terrible management and a toxic work culture. But how does that relate the sort of work my colleagues and I do? We aren't asked to work 14 hours a day for six days a week for months at a time, so how is this relevant?</p>
<p><!-- /wp:paragraph --></p>
<p><!-- wp:paragraph --></p>
<p>Williams' article has a particular quote that I'd like to draw your attention to;</p>
<p><!-- /wp:paragraph --></p>
<p><!-- wp:quote --></p>
<blockquote class="wp-block-quote">
<p>This may be as simple as encouraging a culture of peer pressure: quietly exploiting the natural desire to do well is a method that many of the staff we spoke to had encountered. However, we were also told of managers who noted which staff had put in the most hours when making a potential layoff list.</p>
<p><cite>Ian Williams, "<a href="https://www.theguardian.com/technology/2015/feb/18/crunched-games-industry-exploiting-workforce-ea-spouse-software">Crunched: has the games industry really stopped exploiting its workforce?</a>" - The Guardian, 18 Feb 2015</cite></p>
</blockquote>
<p><!-- /wp:quote --></p>
<p><!-- wp:paragraph --></p>
<p><!-- /wp:paragraph --></p>
<p><!-- wp:paragraph --></p>
<p>For those of you in the analytics community, particularly online and in the visualisation sub community, the bells might now be ringing a lot louder than they were when I was talking about game crunch. It's not about the hours on the clock; it's about the race to the bottom culture which generated those hours on the clock, rooted in the idea that the only way to be successful in technology is to be passionate and perfectionist.</p>
<p><!-- /wp:paragraph --></p>
<p><!-- wp:paragraph --></p>
<p>I find myself having discussions with colleagues in the evening who are doing overtime on client work. I'll message them to ask if they have watched RuPaul's Drag Race yet, and they'll explain that because of development issue X occurring during the day, they're working overtime to catch up on the planned time lost due to the other thing occurring. They couldn't have foreseen the other thing occurring, but hey, a deadline is a deadline. And at the moment (February 2021), they have nothing better to do in the evening, right?</p>
<p><!-- /wp:paragraph --></p>
<p><!-- wp:paragraph --></p>
<p>What people think they have to take on the chin as a cost of working in a competitive industry becomes insidious corrosion on that industry, because it warps expectations of development and how long things take. In the games industry, this becomes the idea that a AAA+ game can be put out in two years, because one studio did it once in two years, and this is similar right? Well we're better than that studio, so we can do twenty months, right? And so on. Part of the encouragement of this is on the client in the first place, who are making a large investment in the game/product and naturally don't want to spend more money than possible. But there's also an expectation on behalf of the consumer. The trolliest of gamers say that devs should simply suck up their overtime complaints because hey, they're working in a dream industry and blah blah blah so much bollocks. From the consumers of our analytics products, I have also seen this start to make an appearance - you guys work in the world's sexiest industry, what do you mean the data quality isn't good enough to add in the four levels of geospatial analysis in 10 minutes? Harvard Business Review told me you guys were magicians?<br>This can be illustrated in the below chart.</p>
<p><!-- /wp:paragraph --></p>
<p><!-- wp:image {"id":563,"sizeSlug":"large","linkDestination":"none","ampLightbox":false} --></p>
<figure class="wp-block-image size-large"><figure class="wp-image-563"><img loading="lazy"  src="https://fragiledata.github.io/StaticHost/media/posts/38/image.png" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" srcset="https://fragiledata.github.io/StaticHost/media/posts/38/responsive/image-xs.png 300w ,https://fragiledata.github.io/StaticHost/media/posts/38/responsive/image-sm.png 480w ,https://fragiledata.github.io/StaticHost/media/posts/38/responsive/image-md.png 768w ,https://fragiledata.github.io/StaticHost/media/posts/38/responsive/image-lg.png 1024w"  alt="This chart shows a cyclical diagram of five blocks. The first block says &quot;client submits woolly requirements for project&quot;. This leads to the second block, which says &quot;arbitrary deadlines provided to client based on said woolly requirements&quot;. This leads to a third block which says, &quot;Devs encounter issues with requirements, general shit happening&quot;. This leads to a fourth block, highlighted in orange, which says &quot;Devs work to fulfil the expectations and deadlines of the client&quot;. This leads to a fifth block, which says &quot;client gets expectations based on this&quot;. This leads back to the first block, completing the circle."></figure>
<figcaption>A quick diagram of how the problem corrodes expectations and development over time.</figcaption>
</figure>
<p><!-- /wp:image --></p>
<p><!-- wp:paragraph --></p>
<p>The unethical implications of working overtime in unexceptional circumstances (if no one is going to die, then go home) is not that your evening is better spent watching Drag Race because stepping away from work is good for your mind, though that is certainly true. The unethical part is the obligation you're putting on the next developer, which could be you, or one of your colleagues, or someone else entirely, confirming unrealistic expectations of development. When someone does this, they are literally making the industry harder to work in for other people. It engenders that race to the bottom which prioritises people with spades of free time, who may have that because of other privileges going on in their lives - and the technology industry wonders why the people at the top of the tree all seem to be a certain way, right?</p>
<p><!-- /wp:paragraph --></p>
<p><!-- wp:paragraph --></p>
<p>If you can't say no to overtime because of your own self worth, then try saying it on behalf of everyone else in your industry.<br><br>Thanks to my brother and colleagues who I've had long conversations with about this over the past few months.</p>
<p><!-- /wp:paragraph --></p>
            ]]>
        </content>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title>NYPD Green? Visualising Police Spend in Selected International Cities</title>
        <author>
            <name>fragiledata</name>
        </author>
        <link href="https://fragiledata.github.io/StaticHost/nypd-green-visualising-police-spend-in-selected-international-cities/"/>
        <id>https://fragiledata.github.io/StaticHost/nypd-green-visualising-police-spend-in-selected-international-cities/</id>
            <category term="Topical Data"/>
            <category term="Data Analysis"/>

        <updated>2022-05-25T19:50:56+01:00</updated>
            <summary>
                <![CDATA[
                        <img src="https://fragiledata.github.io/StaticHost/media/posts/37/nypd-green-dashboard.png" alt="A Tableau dashboard showing three charts examining expenditure on police forces around the world." />
                    The events currently occurring in the United States are at once only&hellip;
                ]]>
            </summary>
        <content type="html">
            <![CDATA[
                    <img src="https://fragiledata.github.io/StaticHost/media/posts/37/nypd-green-dashboard.png" alt="A Tableau dashboard showing three charts examining expenditure on police forces around the world." />
                <p><!-- wp:paragraph --></p>
<p>The events currently occurring in the United States are at once only three weeks, barely six years, and 400 years in the making and do not have an easy resolution because of their manifold causes. One of the clearer roots of the problem is the wretched state of American policing, which has been in dire need of reform for longer than I've been alive; a rallying call of the 2020 movement has been "Defund the Police". I've not looked into police spending to know how much is too much, so I decided to do a comparative analysis of some American and international cities to see what their police budgets looked like.</p>
<p><!-- /wp:paragraph --></p>
<p><!-- wp:heading {"level":3} --></p>
<h3>Why did you select these cities?</h3>
<p><!-- /wp:heading --></p>
<p><!-- wp:paragraph --></p>
<p>Policing is quite complicated. I selected cities on the basis of their policing model being somewhat similar to American cities, which is that the police force is for that city (not the state or area), and that there is broadly one force doing the policing, and the systems of government are generally democratic (as in, no police states). This isn't a perfect comparison - there is often significant variation even within countries, such as France or the UK. However, some places deserve specific notes;</p>
<p><!-- /wp:paragraph --></p>
<p><!-- wp:list --></p>
<ul>
<li>American cities have police departments but they are often within counties and metropolitan areas. This analysis focuses on the area covered by that police force, e.g. Seattle analysis does not include the Kings County Sheriff Dept.</li>
<li>A common refrain in arguments about policing refers to the legality of firearms in the United States. That situation is quite unique, but I included the PSNI in this data as while Northern Ireland is not a city, that force does have frequent experience handling crime involving firearms.</li>
<li>Hong Kong has been subject to major civil unrest for the last year. This loss of trust in the police from the HK locals and the planned changes in public security laws are likely to change the face of policing in the territory, but for now, it is acceptable to include.</li>
<li>This is just flat budget information, and doesn't include what the departments are spending it on. Certain cities and regions will have particular strains on their police budgets which may not apply to others - capital cities will often have to escort and police several thousand embassies and dignitaries for example.</li>
</ul>
<p><!-- /wp:list --></p>
<p><!-- wp:heading {"level":3} --></p>
<h3>OK, what did you find out?</h3>
<p><!-- /wp:heading --></p>
<p><!-- wp:image {"id":538,"sizeSlug":"large"} --></p>
<figure class="wp-block-image size-large"><figure class="wp-image-538"><img loading="lazy"  src="https://fragiledata.github.io/StaticHost/media/posts/37/nypd-green-dashboard.png" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" srcset="https://fragiledata.github.io/StaticHost/media/posts/37/responsive/nypd-green-dashboard-xs.png 300w ,https://fragiledata.github.io/StaticHost/media/posts/37/responsive/nypd-green-dashboard-sm.png 480w ,https://fragiledata.github.io/StaticHost/media/posts/37/responsive/nypd-green-dashboard-md.png 768w ,https://fragiledata.github.io/StaticHost/media/posts/37/responsive/nypd-green-dashboard-lg.png 1024w"  alt="A dashboard showing a set of three charts, demonstrating the funding difference between American and international cities."></figure>
<figcaption>Interact on Tableau Public <a href="https://public.tableau.com/profile/louisa.o.brien#!/vizhome/NYPDGreenComparingAnnualPoliceFunding/Dashboard1">here</a>.</figcaption>
</figure>
<p><!-- /wp:image --></p>
<p><!-- wp:paragraph --></p>
<p>Americans spend a lot on their coppers, and it is notably higher than everyone else. It took me a while to work out what the best way of showing this as a comparison is, but I eventually settled on modelling budget and the number of law enforcement officers by population, and then looked at budget per thousand population for those cities.</p>
<p><!-- /wp:paragraph --></p>
<p><!-- wp:paragraph --></p>
<p>One thing I particular like about the scatter plot is that while I could have used animation to switch between the panels, people who I asked to have a look at the chart generally went off in their own, different, exploratory directions with it, but called certain comparisons to mind;</p>
<p><!-- /wp:paragraph --></p>
<p><!-- wp:list --></p>
<ul>
<li>Berlin and Los Angeles have similar sized populations and similar budgets, but Berlin has 7000 more officers than LA.</li>
<li>Hong Kong and Paris have lower than expected budgets for their population, but have way more officers than expected by the trend line.</li>
<li>Philadelphia has a similar population, budget and number of officers to the PSNI in Northern Ireland.</li>
</ul>
<p><!-- /wp:list --></p>
<p><!-- wp:paragraph --></p>
<p>This is comparing a small number of cities so any model must be taken with a pinch of salt. The linear trend lines applied by Tableau do have significant P-values and suggest something interesting about the scale of difference between US and international cities - a city of 6 million people amongst the international group would have about 20,000 officers and a budget of about £1.7bn, while the same population amongst American cities would have about 26,000 officers, and a budget just over £3bn.</p>
<p><!-- /wp:paragraph --></p>
<p><!-- wp:paragraph --></p>
<p>This analysis doesn't show where the money goes, which would be my next line of enquiry. The American police are distinctly more militarised than most other police forces, but I am not sure if that can fully account for the difference in spend.</p>
<p><!-- /wp:paragraph --></p>
            ]]>
        </content>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title>Should I Scrape This? Planning Notes on Inspecting Websites</title>
        <author>
            <name>fragiledata</name>
        </author>
        <link href="https://fragiledata.github.io/StaticHost/should-i-scrape-this-planning-notes-on-inspecting-websites/"/>
        <id>https://fragiledata.github.io/StaticHost/should-i-scrape-this-planning-notes-on-inspecting-websites/</id>
            <category term="Tools and Tech"/>
            <category term="Data Analysis"/>

        <updated>2022-05-25T19:54:03+01:00</updated>
            <summary>
                <![CDATA[
                        <img src="https://fragiledata.github.io/StaticHost/media/posts/35/five-thirty-eight-scraping-demo.png" alt="An image showing the code underlying FiveThirtyEight&#x27;s football predictions page." />
                    Web scraping can vary between wildly hard (purposefully or otherwise) and being&hellip;
                ]]>
            </summary>
        <content type="html">
            <![CDATA[
                    <img src="https://fragiledata.github.io/StaticHost/media/posts/35/five-thirty-eight-scraping-demo.png" alt="An image showing the code underlying FiveThirtyEight&#x27;s football predictions page." />
                <p>Web scraping can vary between wildly hard (purposefully or otherwise) and being the notch below an open API to extract data. However, there are often some hints you can use to check whether or not a particular site will be one of the easy or hard ones.</p>
<p>Obligatory disclaimer about web scraping: some sites, and owners of those sites, <strong>do not</strong> appreciate being scraped. This might be because scraping effectively is stealing their main commercial product; others might be because of too many inconsiderate scrapers flinging minor DDOS attacks every time they test their scraping tools. Be <a href="https://towardsdatascience.com/ethics-in-web-scraping-b96b18136f01">a mindful scraper</a>, check the site's <a href="https://support.google.com/webmasters/answer/6062608?hl=en">robots.txt file</a>, and be mindful of the owners and purpose of the site itself.</p>
<h4>1. Not all APIs are public</h4>
<p>Just because a data provider doesn't have a public API (though if they have, you should use it), that doesn't mean they aren't using a database organised in a similar way to provision data to users on their site. Sites with more modern protocols tend to fall into this category, which tend to have the following features;</p>
<ul>
<li>The URL paths are well structured</li>
<li>Data objects referred to by codes in the code, not their names (this may be another field).</li>
<li>Browsing through the pages, the layouts tend to approach identical.</li>
</ul>
<figure class="alignnone size-full wp-image-475"><img loading="lazy"  src="https://fragiledata.github.io/StaticHost/media/posts/35/fifa-internal-data-structure.png" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" srcset="https://fragiledata.github.io/StaticHost/media/posts/35/responsive/fifa-internal-data-structure-xs.png 300w ,https://fragiledata.github.io/StaticHost/media/posts/35/responsive/fifa-internal-data-structure-sm.png 480w ,https://fragiledata.github.io/StaticHost/media/posts/35/responsive/fifa-internal-data-structure-md.png 768w ,https://fragiledata.github.io/StaticHost/media/posts/35/responsive/fifa-internal-data-structure-lg.png 1024w"  alt="FIFA internal data structure" width="861" height="1047"></figure> The URLs reveal the order in place behind FIFA's site.</p>
<p>FIFA is a good example of this. Looking at their site for the Women's World Cup, teams, players and games tend to follow specific patterns of presentations in their web pages, because as you can see from the URLs, the data is following a similar kind of pattern to basic API calls. If we open the web console and check out the Sources used in the page, we can see that this is actually the case; FIFA is using an internal API to supply pictures (at a very minimum) to the page.</p>
<figure class="alignnone size-full wp-image-519"><img loading="lazy"  src="https://fragiledata.github.io/StaticHost/media/posts/35/marta-fifa-api-result.jpg" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" srcset="https://fragiledata.github.io/StaticHost/media/posts/35/responsive/marta-fifa-api-result-xs.jpg 300w ,https://fragiledata.github.io/StaticHost/media/posts/35/responsive/marta-fifa-api-result-sm.jpg 480w ,https://fragiledata.github.io/StaticHost/media/posts/35/responsive/marta-fifa-api-result-md.jpg 768w ,https://fragiledata.github.io/StaticHost/media/posts/35/responsive/marta-fifa-api-result-lg.jpg 1024w"  alt="Picture of the API request which returns a photo of Marta, a Brazilian football player." width="604" height="451"></figure> Showing us the API call to load Marta's team picture.</p>
<h4>2. There aren't loads of jazzy JS and other friends plugins</h4>
<p>Add-ins which enhance user experience, whether ranging from chart presentation like D3, or setting specific formats of an experience object like AML, can create speed bumps for any desired scraping. This is because data objects are often obscured by other frames and objects, making them harder to parse in the first place, and introducing layers of potential variation between one page and another, foiling attempts to create templates. Consider this example from <a href="https://projects.fivethirtyeight.com/soccer-predictions/">FiveThirtyEight</a>, with football predictions for selected leads:</p>
<figure class="alignnone size-full wp-image-474"><img loading="lazy"  src="https://fragiledata.github.io/StaticHost/media/posts/35/five-thirty-eight-scraping-demo.png" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" srcset="https://fragiledata.github.io/StaticHost/media/posts/35/responsive/five-thirty-eight-scraping-demo-xs.png 300w ,https://fragiledata.github.io/StaticHost/media/posts/35/responsive/five-thirty-eight-scraping-demo-sm.png 480w ,https://fragiledata.github.io/StaticHost/media/posts/35/responsive/five-thirty-eight-scraping-demo-md.png 768w ,https://fragiledata.github.io/StaticHost/media/posts/35/responsive/five-thirty-eight-scraping-demo-lg.png 1024w"  alt="Five Thirty Eight Scraping Demo" width="1789" height="969"></figure> What makes FiveThirtyEight great for humans to use is a bit of an obstacle to machines.</p>
<p>Inspecting the site, one might hope it would be easy to go in and out to each table and obtain predictions for all the leagues. However, because the link to view the whole table doesn't work like a standard h ref html tag, you might be sorting through the page code for a long time looking for the links, or be employing more sophisticated tools which can simulate page interaction (such as testing tools) in order to load all the data you need.</p>
<h4>3. The object layouts and content standards are <em>actually</em> identical</h4>
<p>During training, when we were learning web scraping at The Data School, <a href="https://twitter.com/KirstyFraser_">a colleague</a> and I had to scrape some financial information from NASDAQ listed companies on Wikipedia. The information we needed was only that which exists in those little info panels we have come to know and love. These panels look essentially the same to humans, but under the hood, and to things which can't read (like machines), they're not.</p>
<figure class="alignnone size-full wp-image-517"><img loading="lazy"  style="color: var(--color-text);" src="https://fragiledata.github.io/StaticHost/media/posts/35/different-wiki-boxes.png" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" srcset="https://fragiledata.github.io/StaticHost/media/posts/35/responsive/different-wiki-boxes-xs.png 300w ,https://fragiledata.github.io/StaticHost/media/posts/35/responsive/different-wiki-boxes-sm.png 480w ,https://fragiledata.github.io/StaticHost/media/posts/35/responsive/different-wiki-boxes-md.png 768w ,https://fragiledata.github.io/StaticHost/media/posts/35/responsive/different-wiki-boxes-lg.png 1024w"  alt="different wiki boxes" width="954" height="600"></figure> The fine line between human comprehension and machine reading.</p>
<p>When sites deliver information in the manner of #1, the content is being delivered to a framework replicated on each page. So scrape one page in a category, and you've probably got 90% of the category if you needed it, as the data input must conform to certain principles for however it's stored. Flexible sites like Wikipedia however, are human edited and do not enforce rigid principles in the same way a database would. My colleague and I struggled to normalise the data in the time limit that we had (which was about 3 hours) because of the different things we had to accommodate, such as multiple dates, different icons, and different ways of writing numbers. Sites like this illustrate the difference between humans grasping comprehension (which can tolerate these variances) and machines "reading", which cannot unless programmed to accommodate them specifically.</p>
<p>Hopefully this provides some help to people planning scraping projects in the future!</p>
            ]]>
        </content>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title>2019-nCoV: Spread In Chinese Provinces</title>
        <author>
            <name>fragiledata</name>
        </author>
        <link href="https://fragiledata.github.io/StaticHost/2019-ncov-spread-in-chinese-provinces/"/>
        <id>https://fragiledata.github.io/StaticHost/2019-ncov-spread-in-chinese-provinces/</id>
            <category term="Visualisations"/>
            <category term="Topical Data"/>
            <category term="News"/>

        <updated>2022-05-25T19:53:04+01:00</updated>
            <summary>
                <![CDATA[
                        <img src="https://fragiledata.github.io/StaticHost/media/posts/36/red-background-2.png" alt="A dashboard showing a small multiples chart of Covid-19 cases in China, in early 2020." />
                    Though my workplace is known mostly as a Tableau consultancy first and&hellip;
                ]]>
            </summary>
        <content type="html">
            <![CDATA[
                    <img src="https://fragiledata.github.io/StaticHost/media/posts/36/red-background-2.png" alt="A dashboard showing a small multiples chart of Covid-19 cases in China, in early 2020." />
                <p>Though my workplace is known mostly as a Tableau consultancy first and foremost, I actually don't spend that much time working with it, as my work tends to be about data engineering (sometimes in advance of someone else using it in Tableau!). This means that in the last year I'm a little out of practice, so I went back to my training (with the help of some timely reminders) to restart my practice; do something you're passionate about, and draw it out first.</p>
<p>Over the past few weeks I have been chatting with friends in China, who are currently in various states of getting bored and back pain from working at home after the Chinese New Year holiday while the authorities try to contain 2019-nCoV. One, home for the holidays in Shaanxi Province, cancelled her flights back to Shanghai tomorrow due to the higher incidence of infection in Shanghai than Shaanxi, and even my Chinese friends in the UK are asking me if I have enough face masks. <a href="https://gisanddata.maps.arcgis.com/apps/opsdashboard/index.html#/bda7594740fd40299423467b48e9ecf6">Johns Hopkins University</a> is maintaining a virus watch dashboard on their GIS server, which is taking and translating data from the China's <a href="http://www.nhc.gov.cn/yjb/s3578/new_list.shtml">National Health Committee</a>. They publish a sheet of this data, linked to on the dashboard, which I decided to use to visualise the spread of the infection over time. So, this is where my thoughts coalesced, after I had seen the data, but before I touched Tableau.</p>
<figure class="alignnone size-full wp-image-482"><img loading="lazy"  src="https://fragiledata.github.io/StaticHost/media/posts/36/img_20200208_192238.jpg" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" srcset="https://fragiledata.github.io/StaticHost/media/posts/36/responsive/img_20200208_192238-xs.jpg 300w ,https://fragiledata.github.io/StaticHost/media/posts/36/responsive/img_20200208_192238-sm.jpg 480w ,https://fragiledata.github.io/StaticHost/media/posts/36/responsive/img_20200208_192238-md.jpg 768w ,https://fragiledata.github.io/StaticHost/media/posts/36/responsive/img_20200208_192238-lg.jpg 1024w"  alt="An image of a note with a hand drawn dashboard plan on it, featuring many boxes and written annotations." width="1600" height="1200"></figure> Condensing some thoughts this morning.</p>
<p>The main thing to build was the trellis chart/tile chart/whatever you want to call it, which I use Ryan Sleeper's summarised techniques <a href="https://playfairdata.com/how-to-make-trellis-tile-small-multiple-maps-in-tableau/">here</a> to do. After building it, I realised that this gives an OK idea of the spread over time, but is it really this confined? When I built the chart, as it was computed using the province name, they are rendered alphabetically. However, for something like this, where geography is important, I decided to go back and do it the hard way, assembling the provinces of China as their own grid, and then hard coding it. As one might expect, these provinces aren't actually laid out in a grid pattern, so I did the best I could to approximate it and put gaps in strategically (e.g. one on the upper right is the Bohai/Yellow Sea). Doing it manually did help me to understand Tableau's plotting better, and also The Information Lab alumni Jevon Da Costa's <a href="https://www.thedataschool.co.uk/jevon-dacosta/understanding-calculation-fields-constructing-trellis-chart-tableau/">blog</a> explaining the calculations.</p>
<p>My plan showed three clear panels; an explanation on the left with some smaller charts, the trellis in the middle, and another panel on the side which I had intended to do a graphic of advice from the WHO about handling the virus. I had underestimated the number of provinces in China so this last panel was put on the maybe pile pretty quickly, as the trellis still needed to be readable. That left the panel on the right, which now started to look to me like a lot of the dashboards I see at work, so that had to be moved. Putting it at the bottom of the sheet, rather than the top of the sheet, was purely a wish to do something different.</p>
<figure class="alignnone size-full wp-image-493"><img loading="lazy"  src="https://fragiledata.github.io/StaticHost/media/posts/36/red-background-2.png" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" srcset="https://fragiledata.github.io/StaticHost/media/posts/36/responsive/red-background-2-xs.png 300w ,https://fragiledata.github.io/StaticHost/media/posts/36/responsive/red-background-2-sm.png 480w ,https://fragiledata.github.io/StaticHost/media/posts/36/responsive/red-background-2-md.png 768w ,https://fragiledata.github.io/StaticHost/media/posts/36/responsive/red-background-2-lg.png 1024w"  alt="Finished design." width="1499" height="999"></figure> The finished product.</p>
<p>The second design choice chart was the mixed bar graph, now on the lower left, which is an odd looking way of representing information - one being a range, and the other just being a value (in this case a percentage). I am a known barbell chart person for ranges, so I banned myself from that, and I still wanted to keep the information (fatality rates and infectiousness) together as they are, together, an important way of assessing viral risk. Although I'm still a bit unsure about this representation, I am happy to accept this for what it is.</p>
<p>Lastly, the colour. Red is a careful choice to use when visualising health related data, as although the red cross is pretty ubiquitous as a symbol of medicine, blue and green prevail often because they are anodyne, "non biological" (as it were) colours. I chose red partly because it is a significant colour in China and partly because our world reaction to the virus has actually been far from anodyne, but instead extremely emotive. The late life and death of <a href="https://www.bbc.co.uk/news/world-asia-china-51403795?intlink_from_url=https://www.bbc.co.uk/news/world/asia/china&amp;link_location=live-reporting-story">Dr Li Wenliang</a>, an ophthalmologist in Wuhan who first noticed that a novel respiratory virus was circulating amongst incoming patients and got a visit from the police for his trouble, inspired passion but also ignited immense anger in China as a point to focus people's dissatisfaction with the way virus containment has been handled, which has involved <a href="https://www.theguardian.com/world/2020/feb/02/shameless-outrage-china-coronavirus-outbreak-mask">supply chain thefts</a> of medical supplies, <a href="https://www.cnbc.com/2020/02/07/hashtag-censored-after-coronavirus-whistleblower-doctors-death.html">suppression of criticism</a> on social media, and <a href="https://www.economist.com/china/2020/01/30/tough-quarantine-measures-have-spread-across-china">increasingly coercive attempts</a> to contain the virus.</p>
<p><strong>Update:</strong> forgot to actually add the <a href="https://public.tableau.com/profile/louisa.o.brien#!/vizhome/2019-nCovSpreadinChineseProvinces/RedBackground">link to the interactive version on Tableau Public</a> (click there if the embedding goes a bit funny on you), where you can hover over the lines and charts for more information.</p>
<div id="viz1581242340111" class="tableauPlaceholder" style="position: relative;"><a href="#"><img loading="lazy" style="border: none;" src="https://fragiledata.github.io/StaticHost/media/posts/36/1_rss.png" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" srcset="https://fragiledata.github.io/StaticHost/media/posts/36/responsive/1_rss-xs.png 300w ,https://fragiledata.github.io/StaticHost/media/posts/36/responsive/1_rss-sm.png 480w ,https://fragiledata.github.io/StaticHost/media/posts/36/responsive/1_rss-md.png 768w ,https://fragiledata.github.io/StaticHost/media/posts/36/responsive/1_rss-lg.png 1024w"  alt=" "></a></div>
            ]]>
        </content>
    </entry>
</feed>
